Guide to the Jenkin Lloyd Jones Papers 1861-1932
University of Chicago Library
Jones, Jenkin Lloyd. Papers
1861-1932
7 linear feet (14 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Jenkin Lloyd Jones, minister, social reformer. The Jenkin Lloyd Jones papers contain correspondence, diaries, lecture notes, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, and photographs. Papers relate to All Souls Church and the Abraham Lincoln Centre. Other topics include the Unitarian Church, the Henry Ford Peace Expedition, the Western Unitarian Conference, the weekly publication Unity, the World's Parliament of Religion, Tower Hill Summer Camp in Wisconsin, and other aspects of Jones' ministry. Correspondents include William C. Gannett, Jane Addams, Susan B. Anthony, Francis W. Parker, Frank Lloyd Wright, and Booker T. Washington. Also contains papers of Edith Lackersteen Lloyd Jones, Jones's second wife; her daughter, Mary Lackersteen; and the Lackersteen family.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Jenkin Lloyd Jones, born in Wales in 1843, was brought to the United States by his parents in 1844 and was raised on a pioneer farm in Wisconsin. Several of his ancestors, including Jenkin Jones and David Lloyd, had been pioneer ministers in the Arminian movement in Wales. Jones enlisted in the Union army during the Civil War as a matter of conscience, fighting in the battles of Vicksburg, Chattanooga, and Missionary Ridge. He was mustered out in 1865 as a confirmed opponent to war, a position he maintained throughout his life. Upon graduation in 1870 from Meadville Theological Seminary in Pennsylvania, he was ordained a Unitarian minister, serving at Winnetka, Illinois, 1870-71, and Janesville, Wisconsin, 1871-80. In 1882, Jones began missionary work on the south side of Chicago, which resulted in the organization of All Souls Church, of which he remained pastor until his death. Jones early in his career was active in forming "Mutual Improvement Clubs", a new idea in church life in the 1870's, a movement that spread and eventually became the "Unity Clubs" found in almost all Unitarian churches of the Middle West.
In 1874, Jones became secretary of the Western Unitarian Conference, a position he held until 1884. He infused new life into the dying organization, moved its headquarters to Chicago in 1880, and devoted all of his time to the Conference, giving up his church in Janesville. He helped found the weekly magazine Unity in 1878, dedicated to "Freedom, Fellowship and Character in Religion," and remained its editor until his death. He set up a Sunday School society which published numerous lessons and vigorous tract-publications. But Jones also led a movement within the Western Conference for ethical rather than theological unanimity as the basis for liberal fellowship. This issue erupted at the Cincinnati meeting of the Conference in 1886, where many of the conservative churches withdrew and the eastern branch of the movement set up a rival organization. Until the breach was healed in 1894, Jones used his editorship of Unity to advance the liberal cause and the magazine became the mouthpiece of the liberal party within the movement.
Soon after the foundation of All Souls Church Jones dropped the word "Unitarian". He felt that denomination built a fence around religion and he did not want his church, even by remote implication, to exclude anyone. This church became the nucleus of Jones' even more ambitious project, the Abraham Lincoln Centre, founded in 1905. Lincoln Centre was a combination social, civic and religious center in its early years, with All Souls Church at its core, but it also provided a gymnasium, manual training, domestic science classes, reading rooms, libraries, lecture courses, as well as study classes in subjects including religion, citizenship, literature. Jones' idea of universal religion inspired the World's Parliament of Religion, in connection with the Columbian Exposition in Chicago in 1893. He was the moving force behind the movement as well as its General Secretary. He also sailed on the Ford Peace Ship Mission in December 1915 and became the chairman of the Committee of Administration after the withdrawal of Henry Ford due to illness. He maintained his pacifist viewpoint until his death and in 1918 his editorial opposition in Unity to war in general and American participation in World War I led to the suspension of mailing privileges of the magazine by the United States Postmaster-General. Jones also founded the Tower Hill (Wisconsin) Summer Camp in 1889, which gave systematic lectures on literary and liberal religious subjects.
He was the author of numerous works, among them: An Artilleryman's Diary (1914); The Faith That Makes Faithful, with W. C. Gannett (1886); Jess: Bits of Wayside Gospel (1899); A Search for an Infidel (1901); and Love for the Battletorn Peoples (1916). He received an honorary LL.D. from the University of Wisconsin in 1909.
Susan Barber, Jones' first wife died in 1911. In 1915, he married Edith Lackersteen, his longtime associate at Lincoln Centre. Jones died at Tower Hill, Wisconsin, in 1918. Edith Lloyd Jones died in 1932.
Scope Note
The Jenkin Lloyd Jones papers contain correspondence, diaries, lecture notes, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, and photographs. Papers relate to All Souls Church and the Abraham Lincoln Centre. Other topics include the Unitarian Church, the Henry Ford Peace Expedition, the Western Unitarian Conference, the weekly publication Unity, the World's Parliament of Religion, Tower Hill Summer Camp in Wisconsin, and other aspects of Jones' ministry. Correspondents include William C. Gannett, Jane Addams, Susan B. Anthony, Francis W. Parker, Frank Lloyd Wright, and Booker T. Washington. Also contains papers of Edith Lackersteen Lloyd Jones, Jones's second wife; her daughter, Mary Lackersteen; and the Lackersteen family.
The collection is organized into seven series: Series I: Jenkin Lloyd Jones Correspondence; Series II: Henry Ford Peace Expedition, 1915-1916; Series III: Miscellaneous Jenkins Lloyd Jones Materials; Series IV: Edith Lackersteen Jones Correspondence; Series V: Mary Lackersteen Papers; Series VI: Abraham Lincoln Centre Materials; and Series VII: Photographs.
Series VII notably includes images of Jenkin Lloyd Jones, Edith Lloyd Jones and others aboard the Ford Peace Ship in 1915, and includes images of the Hillside Home School, a co-educational boarding school established by Jenkin Lloyd Jones’ sisters Jane and Nell in 1887 and located near Spring Green, Wisconsin. The building was designed by their nephew, Frank Lloyd Wright, then an amateur architect in Chicago. After the school closed down in 1915, Frank Lloyd Wright inherited the building.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Addams, Jane, 1860-1935; Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906; Gannett, William C. (William Channing), 1840-1923; Jones, Edith Lloyd; Jones, Jenkin Lloyd, 1843-1918; Parker, Francis W. (Francis Wayland), 1837-1902; Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915; Abraham Lincoln Centre (Chicago, Ill.); All Souls Church (Chicago, Ill.); Henry Ford Peace Expedition (1915-1916); World's Parliament of Religions (1893: Chicago, Ill.); Unitarian churches
INVENTORY
- Series I: Jenkin Lloyd Jones Correspondence
  - Copies and excerpts of letters 1861-1872 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Addams, Jane (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allen, Joseph H. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anthony, Susan B. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ba (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Be-Bl (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bo (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Br (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bu (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Barrows, John H. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Barrows, Samuel J. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Batchelor, George (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bickerdyke, Mary Ann Ball (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bonet-Maury, Gaston (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ca-Ch (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cl-Cr (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Chadwick, John W. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Coffin, William A. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Collyer, Robert (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Crooker, J. H. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Crothers, Samuel M. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - D (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dharmapala, H. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Duncan, Lewis J. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - E (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Emerson, Edward W. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Emerson, Edward W. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Fa-Fi (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Fl-Fu (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Fiske, John (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ga-Gi (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Go-Gr (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Gannett, William C. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Gannett, William C. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Gannett, William C. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gannett, William C. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gunsaulus, Frank W. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Ha (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - He (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Hi (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ho (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hu (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hale, Edward E. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Harper, William R. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Heath, Helen S. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Herford, Brooke (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Higginson, Thomas W. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hosmer, Frederick L. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - I-Je (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Jo-Ju (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Jones, Susan (Mrs. Jenkin Lloyd Jones) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ka-Kel (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ken-Ky (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Kent, William (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Kent, William (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Kerr, Thomas (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - La (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Le (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Li-Ly (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Learned, J. C. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Mac-Maco (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Mag-Mar (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Mas-Max (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Me-Mi (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Mo-More (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Morr-Mu (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Martin, Alfred W. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Mead, Edwin D. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - N-O (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Nagarkar, B. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pa (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Pe (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Ph-Pu (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Parker, Francis W. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Powell, Edward P. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ra-Ri (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ro-Ru (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Sa (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Sc-Se (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Sh (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Si-Sn (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - So-Sp (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Sta-Ste (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Sto-Sw (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Salter, William M. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Savage, Minot J. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Snyder, John (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Sunderland, J. T. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Ta-Thom (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Thomp-Thw (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - To-Tu (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Thomas, H. W. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - U-V (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Wa-War (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Was (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - We (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Wh (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Wi (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Wo-Wr (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Webb, Alexander Russell (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Wendte, Charles W. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Willard, Frances E. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Wooley, Celia P. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Y (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Z (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Index cards (by year) to correspondence-1880—1888 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Index cards (by year) to correspondence – 1890-1893 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Index cards (by year) to correspondence-1894-1896 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Index cards (by year) to correspondence-1897, 1899-1901 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Typed extracts of Jenkin Lloyd Jones' letters-December 17, 1888-April 16, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Typed extracts of Jenkin Lloyd Jones' letters-April 17, 1889-July 5, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Index cards to Jenkin Lloyd Jones' correspondence-1888-1889 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1889, 1894-1898 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1899-1901 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1902-1903 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1906-1907 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1910-1913 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Jones to Edith Lackersteen Jones, Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series II: Henry Ford Peace Expedition, 1915-1916
  - Correspondence-November-December, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence-January, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence-January, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence-February, 1916; undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Personal letters Edith Lloyd and Family (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Copy of minutes of the meetings of the Committee on Administration (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Plan of expedition, manifestos, statements, petitions (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous programs and itineraries (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - The Argosy-mimeographed newspaper published aboard ship during Peace Expedition-Nos. 1-8 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Invitations, brochures of Peace Expedition, calling cards (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Clippings concerning Peace Expedition (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Pamphlets published by Peace Expedition (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Copy of Jenkin Lloyd Jones' affadavit for passport, train pass, etc. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Articles by Jenkin Lloyd Jones (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Edith Lloyd Jones' diary (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Series III: Miscellaneous Jenkins Lloyd Jones Materials
  - Notes on proposed Abraham Lincoln book (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Notes on proposed farm book; galley proofs (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Notes on proposed peace book (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Printed sermons of Jenkin Lloyd Jones (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Printed sermons of Jenkin Lloyd Jones (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Printed pamphlets edited by Jenkin Lloyd Jones (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Biographical sketches (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Material on ancestors and relatives of Jenkin Lloyd Jones; minutes of meeting of Lloyd Jones Family, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Christian Register articles on Jenkin Lloyd Jones (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Sentinel article on Jenkin Lloyd Jones (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Table of contents of proposed autobiography; citation on honorary LL.D.; eulogy by Dr. Farville; unveiling of bas relief of Jenkin Lloyd Jones; publication list of Jenkin Lloyd Jones; etc. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Souvenir book on 1897 European tour (ticket stubs, calling cards, bills, and correspondence) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook on life of Jenkin Lloyd Jones (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Practical Piety: Four Discourses Delivered at Central Music Hall, Chicago (1887) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Diary-September, 1866-April 22, 1867 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Account book-1866-1870 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Lecture notes taken at Meadville Theological Seminary-Rhetoric (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Lecture notes taken at Meadville Theological Seminary-Ethics, Art, Impersonal Religions (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Lecture notes taken at Meadville Theological Seminary – Elocution, Church in the Dark Ages (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lecture notes taken at Meadville Theological Seminary-Acts of the Apostles, Gospel of John (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Lecture notes taken at Meadville Theological Seminary – Matthew, Luke (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Lecture notes taken at Meadville Theological Seminary-Old Testament, New Testament (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lecture notes taken at Meadville Theological Seminary – Literature of the New Testament (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Lecture notes taken at Meadville Theological Seminary-Index (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Notes and clippings on "Death" (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Notes and clippings on "Music" (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Notes and clippings on "Love" (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Notes and clippings on "Caliban and Saul" (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Notes and clippings on "Art" (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Notes and clippings on "Songs and Ballads" (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Programs, Abstracts and Memorabilia from courses arranged by Jenkin Lloyd Jones at All Souls Church, Lincoln Center and University of Chicago Extension Division (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous material concerning Tower Hill, Wisconsin (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Impressions of Tower Hill (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence concerning donation of Tower Hill as Jenkin Lloyd Jones State Park (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - R. W. Emerson, The Conduct of Life (Boston: Ticknor and Fields, 1861). Interleaved and with marginal autograph notes by Jenkin Lloyd Jones. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Clippings on dedication of Jenkin Lloyd Jones State Park (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Tower Hill Guest Book (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Handwritten Dictionary (words beginning with A only) with quotations illustrating usage (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Edith Lackersteen Jones Correspondence
  - Correspondence to Edith Lloyd Jones-A-C (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to Edith Lloyd Jones-D-G (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence to Edith Lloyd Jones-H-J (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence to Edith Lloyd Jones-K-Q (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence to Edith Lloyd Jones-R-Z (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Edith Lloyd Jones-A-C (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from Edith Lloyd Jones-D-Q (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from Edith Lloyd Jones-R-Z, unidentified (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Edith Lloyd Jones to Helen Swift Neilson (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Edith Lloyd Jones to Helen Swift Neilson (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Helen Swift Neilson to Edith Lloyd Jones (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Helen Swift Neilson to Edith Lloyd Jones (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Helen Swift Neilson to Edith Lloyd Jones (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Helen Swift Neilson to Edith Lloyd Jones (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Edith Lloyd Jones to Mary Lackersteen (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Edith Lloyd Jones to Mary Lackersteen (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Harold Lackersteen to Edith Lloyd Jones (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Ruth Lackersteen Rizer to Edith Lloyd Jones (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Robert Rizer to Edith Lloyd Jones (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Wynne Lackersteen to Edith Lloyd Jones (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Wynne Lackersteen to Edith Lloyd Jones (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Edith Lloyd Jones Material (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Helen Swift Neilson Material (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Series V: Mary Lackersteen Papers
  - Harold Lackersteen to Mary Lackersteen (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Ruth Lackersteen Rizer to Mary Lackersteen (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Robert Rizer to Mary Lackersteen (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Wynne Lackersteen to Mary Lackersteen (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - M. H. Lackersteen to Mary and Wynne Lackersteen (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence to Mary Lackersteen-A-L (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence to Mary Lackersteen-M-Z (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence to Mary Lackersteen-May Johnson (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence to Mary Lackersteen-Helen Swift Neilson (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence to Mary Lackersteen-Mary Pinckney (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence to Mary Lackersteen-Mary Pinckney (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence to Mary Lackersteen-Olive Cole Smith (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from Mary Lackersteen (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence and other material concerning Community House, Cedar Rapids, Iowa (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Report by Mary Lackersteen on Oakland Community, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - M. H. Lackersteen Medical Notebooks (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - M. H. Lackersteen Medical Notebook (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Lackersteen material (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Series VI: Abraham Lincoln Center Materials
  - Lincoln Center Year Book, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Lincoln Center Year Book, 1919 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Lincoln Center Year Book, 1920 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Lincoln Center Year Book, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Unity, December 17-24, 1903 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Unity, February 22; March 1, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Unity, March 7; July 4, 11, 18, 25; August 1, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Unity, September 19, 26; October 31; November 7, 28; December 5, 12, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Unity, April 17, 24, 1933; January 20, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Unity, July 1, year? August 5, 1940; August, September, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of meeting of board of Unity Publishing Co., April 7, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified notes (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous material on All Souls Church and Lincoln Center (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous material on All Souls Church and Lincoln Center (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous material on All Souls Church and Lincoln Center (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous material on All Souls Church and Lincoln Center (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified documents and papers concerning administrative difficulties at Lincoln Center (circa 1920) (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Susan Quackenbush correspondence and miscellaneous material (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Richard Lloyd Jones correspondence (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence and reports concerning disposition of Jenkin Lloyd Jones manuscripts and papers (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Series VII: Photographs
  - Early photographs of Jenkin Lloyd Jones, 1867-1896 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Portraits of Jenkin Lloyd Jones, circa 1915 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of a painting of Jenkin Lloyd Jones, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Jenkin Lloyd Jones, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Edith Lloyd Jones, her family and associates, circa 1915 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of the Lackersteen family, circa 1901 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Jenkin Lloyd Jones and Edith Lloyd Jones on the Ford Peace expedition, 1915, including photographs and postcards of a Belgian refugee camp, circa 1914-1918 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Portraits of Jenkin Lloyd Jones’ relatives, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Photograph of Community House, Cedar Rapids, Iowa, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Photographs and Photographs of the Lincoln Center, circa 1915 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook of the Lincoln Center summer camp, circa 1919 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Photograph album, Hillside Home School, circa 1900-1915 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Tower Hill and Hillside Home School, 1890-1900 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Tower Hill, circa 1915 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of animals and farmers, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Photographs of landscapes, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Photographs of mother and children, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Photographs and portraits of children, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Photographs and portraits of men, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Photographs and portraits of women, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
  - Negatives, Camp, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Negatives, Camp, boys, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Negatives, Clear Lake, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Negatives, Eastern trip, Niagara, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Negatives, Field day, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Negatives, Gym class, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Negatives, Tower Hill, circa 1915 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Negatives, Tower Hill, circa 1915 (Box 14, Folder 12)